quill.org 2019-12-19

# Quill.org — Interactive Writing and Grammar

* * *

* * *

Empirical Resolution Inc. (d/b/a Quill.org) (“we” or “us”), values your privacy and we are committed to creating a secure environment across our services, including our application programming interface, website and other online services (collectively, our “Website”). We use the data we collect to provide users with a high quality engaging experience and fulfill our mission of creating an active learning environment and helping students take charge of their education. Because we gather certain types of information about the users of the Website, we believe you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the use of the information we collect. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our Website. Please make sure that you read the terms of this policy and any privacy policies that you enter into with parties other than us, including your employer or educational institution, as those policies may also explain how your personal information is used by those parties.

Your use of our Website means that you specifically and expressly consent to all practices described below in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, as amended from time to time. Any information you provide to us or the Website, along with your use of the Website, is subject to the terms in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, as amended from time to time.

## How data is used and collected:

 **Quill.org collects the following data about our users and their use of our Website.**

  *  **Personal information.**

By registering with or using the Website, you may provide to Quill.org what is generally called “personally identifiable information” (such as your email address, name) that can be used to identify you, as well as demographic information such as your age, gender and interests. Through the rest of this Privacy Policy, such information will be referred to as “Personal Information.”

  *  **User-provided information and information about use of website.**

In addition to Personal Information, we may collect information about your use of certain Website features, such as the number of activities you have completed, your time spent on various activities, and your scores on various activities. This information allows us to make a better, more personalized experience and provides us with data that we use to improve the Website. We may also request information for purposes such as the provision of customer service and support, billing, network management, customer surveys, newsletter subscriptions, user group memberships, event registration and sponsorship, offers of related services, and other exchanges of information.

We may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available in certain areas of the Website. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your Personal Information.

Any content you submit to, or make available on, the Website (“User-Created Content”) shall be your property and you represent that such User-Created Content does not infringe on the intellectual property of any third party. You hereby grant us a perpetual, irrevocable, royalty-free, sublicenseable worldwide license to use and display such User-Created Content.

  *  **Information obtained from other users and third parties.**

Some features on the Website may be used that allow other users or third parties to provide us information, some of which may be Personal Information. For example, a parent may register an account for their child and provide us with certain information, such as the child’s name or one of our partners may send us information when you access our Website through their Website or service.

  *  **Technical information.**

We may record technical information such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, internet service provider, browser type, operating system, the dates and times the Website is visited, referring or exit pages, and other data which tracks users' access to the Website. This data may be analyzed for the aggregate trends they reveal about our users and how the users use the Website.

## How we use this information:

  *  **To personalize and maximize learning experiences.**

The information provided may be used to better your experience on the Website. For example, we may track which activities need to be finished and which ones are completed, and then use this information to suggest areas you may wish to work on.

  *  **To understand how users engage with the Website.**

We use information provided by, or collected from, users to create new features, analyze trends and metrics, and learn information about our users’ preferences.

## Limitations on access to your Personal Information by employees and authorized parties:

Our employees and affiliates will not access your Personal Information without a specific reason to do so. Often this reason will be to better serve you in the event of a support issue (for example, we may look up your operating system and web browser if you write to us saying you are having a problem with the Website).

## How your data is shared and transferred.

 **We disclose user information only as described below:**

  *  **Student’s personal information may be shared with students’ schools and teachers.**

When a student joins a class, their data, including their name, username and scores, becomes available to the teacher who created that class. This information may also be shared with other agents within the school, including other teachers and the administration.

  *  **Aggregated and anonymous data may be shared.**

We will occasionally share aggregated and/or anonymized data with partners for research, evaluation, consulting or other business purposes. When this occurs, no Personal Information will be shared, however, other information, such as your city, grade level, or performance may be shared.

  *  **As legally required**

In response to court orders, warrants, or subpoenas, and other situations where required by law, we may share user information. We will take reasonable steps to notify users of this sharing as soon as possible.

  *  **Change of business**

If we acquire, merge with, or are acquired by another organization, in whole or in part, the information we have collected may be transferred to and/or shared with the other organization and its affiliates. In such case, the organization receiving the personal information will be obligated to follow the terms of this privacy policy.

  *  **When appropriate or necessary to protect our interests**

We may share information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to enforce the Terms of Use or to protect us against liability, unlawful or fraudulent uses, or to defend ourselves against third-party allegations or claims. We may also share this information for security reasons, such as to defend the integrity of our website. Your information may also be shared to protect the personal safety, rights, or property of Quill.org, its users, and others.

  *  **Service providers**

We may share information with our service providers.

  *  **Partners**

We may share information about aggregated and/or anonymized data with our partners.

## Your options and choices in our data use, collection, and transfer:

  *  **You can choose to not provide us with Personal Information**

You may use the Website anonymously without providing any Personal Information. If you choose to do this, you will still have access to all of our lessons and content, but some Website features may not work and your progress will not be saved.

  *  **You can view your Personal Information**

You can view certain personal information by logging into our website, and can request to view any other personal information by contacting us at hello@quill.org, or sending a request in writing to the address listed below.

  *  **Your Personal Information can be corrected, edited, or deleted**

To ensure that you have control over your information, we will respond as quickly as possible to any request to correct, edit or delete Personal Information. If you would like this information changed or removed, please contact us at hello@quill.org, or send a request in writing to the address listed below.

## Data Retention

We will retain your or your student's personal information, including after the school term in which you or your student uses the Services, for only as long as is reasonably necessary to fulfill the purpose for which the information was collected. Generally, Quill will delete a user's personal information 4 years after the user's last login to the Services.

## Children Users

### Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

To comply with COPPA, we only collect Personal Information from children under 13 after the student’s school, district or teacher has agreed to obtain parental consent for that child to use our Website and to provide us with Personal Information.

While parents or guardians of children under 13 may sign up their child and provide us with Personal Information about the child, no child under 13 may sign up with us or send us Personal Information unless they are signing up through their school, district or teacher, and that school, district or teacher has obtained parental or guardian consent to use our Website and provide us with Personal Information.

If you are under 13, do not send us any Personal Information unless you are signing up through your school, district or teacher, and that school, district or teacher has obtained parental consent for you to use our Website and provide us with Personal Information.

If we find any users who are under 13 and have shared Personal Information with us without signing up through a school, district or teacher that has obtained parental consent to use our Website and provide us with Personal Information, we will delete this information as quickly as possible. If you are aware, or become aware, of any users who have violated any part of this section, please email us at hello@quill.org so that we can investigate.

If you are signing up for the Website and creating accounts on behalf of student(s), you represent and warrant that you are either (a) a teacher or school administrator or otherwise authorized by a school or district to sign up on behalf of students, or (b) the parent of such student(s). If you are a school, district, or teacher, you represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and all similar applicable laws, meaning that you must obtain advance written consent from all parents or guardians whose children under 13 will be accessing the Services. When obtaining consent, you must provide parents and guardians with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. You must keep all consents on file and provide them to us if we request them. If you are a teacher, you represent and warrant that you have permission and authorization from your school and/or district to use the Services as part of your curriculum, and for purposes of COPPA compliance, you represent and warrant that you are agreeing to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use on behalf of your school and/or district.

## How we handle data security

  *  **Keeping your information secure**

To protect your Personal Information, account information, and privacy, we may require you to login using a password before accessing certain parts of the Website. We urge you to create a strong password and keep this information safe.

  *  **We try to keep secure the Website and Personal Information within, but there are no guarantees.**

We use a number of techniques, including technological, social and procedural methods designed to keep your information safe. These include following industry practices, working with cyber security consultants, and more. While we take reasonable steps to protect your information, we neither ensure nor warrant that information transmitted to or by us is secure, and you provide us with this information at your own risk.

  *  **You will be notified electronically or through the Website if there has been a security incident that may affect you.**

If a security incident involving your Personal Information does occur, we will notify you and any other users that may have been affected as soon as possible after we learn of the security incident. This notification may occur electronically, or via a notice posted on the Website.

## Links to third party sites

In some cases, the Website may link to third party websites. These links may include social media pages, partner organizations, or any other website. We cannot control the activities or content that exists on these sites, and they may change without our knowledge. This Privacy Policy does not apply to those websites, or any other website that is not part of the Website.

## Changes and updates to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any changes, we will change the last revised date listed below. The revised Privacy Policy will become effective upon such posting.

If we make any material changes to this policy, we will provide notice to the email address we have on record for each account holder. For material changes regarding use or collection of data, we will provide choices and additional information regarding the collection of such data before it is used in any manner inconsistent with the terms initially provided to users. You are responsible at all times for keeping that email address up to date.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, comments, or would like to know what Personal Information has been collected about you, please contact us by emailing hello@quill.org or writing to:

Empirical Resolution Inc.   
41 E 11th St   
11th Floor   
New York, NY 10003

 _updated 9/26/18_
